

Donald McLamb

Full-Stack Web Developer

Contact Me:



816.914.7334



mclamb.donald@gmail.com



cyberdesigns.io



http://github.com/dmc2015

Primary Skills:









Other Technical Skills:

Management & Other IT Skills

- PostgreSQL
- Foundations
- Github
- AWS
- Heroku
- Microsoft Server 2012
- Vagrant
- Ansible

Methodologies & Processes

- Agile Design
- Entity Relational Diagram
- MVC
- Wire framing

Misc. Software

- Image Editing Software
- Bash
- Vim
- Atom

Overview

A skilled full-stack developer with a cybersecurity and software support background, dedicated to the safety and security of information as well as the user experience. Seasoned problem solver with a strong drive to develop useful, secure applications and software that promote solutions to relevant security concerns.

Industry Experience and Projects

Cyberdesigns.io, Gaithersburg MD, June 2015 - Present

A freelance company I started to continue the development of my portfolio.

VoxPopuli - voxpopuli-.herokuapp.com, July 2015 - September 2015 A individual MEAN stack, based on a Reddit clone. The application is designed to share information and public opninion among users.

Technologies used: HTML, Mongo, Express, Angular, Node, Gulp, CSS, Bootstrap, Passport

Formula I Stats - <u>formula-1-stats.herokuapp.com</u>, September 2015 A Angular.js and Node based app using a external API to display Formula-1 race stats. It uses a custom mapping object to keep the app DRY. Future iterations will allow users to pick what year they can see stats on.

Technologies used: HTML, Angular, Node, Bootstrap, CSS, Gulp

DayTrackr - <u>daytrackr.meteor.com</u>, *June 2015 - Present*A individual project, currently in a prototype state using Meteor.js. It is mobile compatibile and responsive. The end result will be a multi-platform scheduler and alarm app.

Technologies used: Meteor.js, HTML, CSS, Foundations

General Assembly, Washington DC, *March 2015 - June 2015*WDI student at a full-stack web development program focused on best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development.

SecurityPulse - securitypulse.herokuapp.com, May 2015 - May 2015 A individual project that was developed to centralizing cyber security information while also providing a resource for people to discuss cybersecurity issues. Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, Pry, ActiveRecord, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, Devise, HTML, CSS

DC Science Hackathon, Washington DC, *March 2015 - March 2015*A 2-day event to develop something creative and impactful while collaborating.

PoliConnect - policonnect.org, March 2015 - July 2015

A group project for a DC Science Hackathon, the app's function is to connect policy makers to experts anonymously so that productive debates can take place.

Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, FFaker, AWS, Strategiezed Security Solutions

Employment History

Sunlight Foundation, Washington DC, October 2015 - Present

Software Developer

- Debugging existing django project
- Implementing and supporting scrapping frameworks
- Using tools to streamline devop processes
- Writing technical documentation for solutions and users

Axxis Software, Gaithersburg MD, May 2013 - April 2015

Software Support Engineer

- Supported customers, IT staff and performed server migrations
- Reviewed and analyzed system logs to find environmental issues
- Advised on security practices, server configuration

Motionsoft, Rockville MD, April 2012 - May 2013

Software Support Engineer

- Implemented and trained customers on CMS systems
- Troubleshooted hand key scanners, control access systems
- Executed SQL queries to troubleshoot issues

Education

Springboard - Online UX Course, December 2015 - February 2016

Codementors - Online Angular JS Course, June 2015 - August 2015

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive, March 2015 - June 2015

UMUC - Masters of Science - Cybersecurity, September 2011 - December 2014

Towson University - BS Sociology & Psychology, September 2006 - December 2010